#### **Steve Hansen**

U.S. Citizen SSN: 523-66-6529

Address: 2644 Donovan, Bellingham WA 98225 Phone: (360) 647-8414

Email: steven.e.hansen@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Steve is an experienced project manager, software architect, object-oriented analyst and designer, software developer and consultant. His background extends through workflow and business process modeling systems; Siebel customer relationship manager; XML and XSLT; Oracle, SQL Server and other database systems; C++ and Java languages; webbased software development, messaging and networking. He is experienced in the full range of Linux, Unix and Windows-based systems.

#### PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

2005 - Position Title: Project Manager

Present Company: Alfa Consult, 142-144 rue Albert Unden, L-2652 Luxembourg

- Project manager for development of a Siebel-based customer relationship management (CRM) systems for Iraq's National Communication and Media Commission (NCMC) and the Iraq Telephone and Post Commission (ITPC)
  - o Management of team of 10 internal and external CRM developers
  - o Requirements definition and writing
  - o Development and delivery of training classes for CRM Iraqi users
  - o Development of administration manuals and users guides
  - Siebel and Oracle database development
- Project manager for development of wireless and DSL broadband internet service provider (<a href="www.skycom-iq.com">www.skycom-iq.com</a>) project featuring WiMAX technology
  - o Management of team of 15 internal and external developers
  - Management of development of billing and AAA (authentication, authorization and accounting) system
  - Defined selection criteria and managed product evaluations for
    - Billing systems
    - Email systems
    - WiMAX products
  - o Management of development of web portal for SkyCom internet services
  - Coordinated laboratory development and live testing events of integrated WiMAX service in Luxembourg
  - Coordination and writing of user's guide, administration manual and programmer's documentation
  - Training by ATDI in operation of ICS Telecom NG network design tool (May 2007)

2005 - **Position Title: Owner** 

Present Company: Fairhaven IT, Bellingham, WA

- Terrain evaluator software for Chinook Wind
  - o Performed several runs with existing R/Excel/SQL Server system

- o Converted the evaluator to use a MySQL database
- o Improved error catching, improved the tool's workflow
- o Wrote documentation for installing all components and using the tool
- Partner in GoTakeOff building materials program
  - o SQL Server database development and maintenance
  - o Enhancement and maintenance of ASP-based web software for calculating materials needed for a new house construction or an addition
  - o See www.gotakeoff.com

#### 2004 - Position Title: XVT Project Lead

2005

#### Company: Providence Software, 1143 Executive Circle, Cary, NC 27511

• Project leader for release 5.6 of the XVT cross-platform graphical interface product line for C/C++/Java (www.xvt.com)

### **Position Title: Software Architect**

# 2004 Company: RDMA, S.A., Luxembourg

- Development of a peer-to-peer knowledge and document management system, written in Java
- Consultant in Java, C++ and Oracle database development for search engine of European Union's Community Research and Development Information Service. (It can be viewed at www.cordis.lu)

# 2001 - Position Title: Senior Software Engineer 2002 - Company: Alfa Consult 142-144 rue Alfa

#### Company: Alfa Consult, 142-144 rue Albert Unden, L-2652 Luxembourg

- Lead developer for version 2 of Alfa Consult's Java channel/adapter-based Business Information Systems (BIS) framework
- Designed and implemented multi-threaded asynchronous processing support for the BIS framework
- Designed and implemented a transaction-based guaranteed messaging infrastructure component using BIS channels and a Tibco RVTX adapter
- Designed and implemented XSLT Java code generation of BIS framework application extensions from XML configuration
- Wrote documentation for the BIS framework

#### **Position Title: Senior Software Consultant**

### Company: Dokken Software Inc., 100 N. 27<sup>th</sup> St., Suite 250, Billings, MT 59101

- Developed a requirements specification for the implementation of a Business Process Management System (BPMS) for a business collaboration product, for bConnectedSoftware, Inc.
- Designed and developed an object-to-relational backflow server for a next-generation railway control system. (C++, Oracle, Versant ODBMS)
- Participated in design and development of a proof-of-concept prototype for DSI's business workflow toolkit, under a Phase I SBIR award from NIST, specializing in Enterprise Java Bean (EJB) development (Java, EJB)

## Position Title: Senior Software Engineer Company: Genomica Corporation, 1745 38<sup>th</sup> St., Boulder, CO 80301

- Participated as a Java developer in the development of reference database software systems serving human genome project scientific researchers, using JDBC/SQLJ and Oracle
- Participated in the design and prototype implementation of an EJB-based API for accessing the database. Investigated using EJB/JSP within the API framework

# Position Title: Senior Software Engineer Company: bCandid Corp., 2465 Central Ave., Suite 210, Boulder, CO 80301

- Developed web-based B2B e-commerce solutions using Java, JDBC, Oracle 8i, Perl. XML
- Developed web-based Usenet discussion software, using Java, C++, JDBC, Perl, and XML

# 1993 - Position Title: Senior Consulting Engineer 1999 Company: RogueWave Software, 5500 Flatiron Pkwy, Boulder, CO 80301

- Redesigned and developed loan risk analysis applications for Bank of America, San Francisco (Sybase)
- Designed and developed a multi-threaded business event monitoring system, analyzing Oracle data for Cedel investment bank, Luxembourg
- Upgraded Chase Manhattan banking applications as an architecture team member in a 10-person application infrastructure group (CORBA)
- Served as team leader on sub-contract to design and develop Internet and Oraclebased news search engine
- Served as project manager, lead designer and lead engineer on 10-person, 2 1/2
  year project developing computer-aided design and manufacturing application used
  to control printed circuit board manufacturing equipment for Fuji Machine
  America
- Completed consulting engineering assignments, which included troubleshooting, architecture, and custom object-oriented design and C++ class development as well as on-site formal and informal training. Customers included Northern Telecom, National Semiconductor, EDS, Lawrence Livermore Labs, Dun & Bradstreet, Chase Manhattan, Motorola, Netscape, and Lucent
- Taught C++, DBTools.h++, and Threads.h++ product training courses

# 1989 - Independent Software Consultant, Auburn, Washington 1993 - Developed a Petri Net modeling system in a U.S. New S

- Developed a Petri Net modeling system in a U.S. Navy SBIR Phase II project as part of a consulting engagement with Software Consultants International, Ltd., Kent, Washington.
- Developed a cooling tower plume modeling application as part of a consulting engagement with Envirometrics, Seattle, Washington
- Developed and taught C and C++ language courses. Customers included IBM, U.S. Navy, Canadian Air Force.
- Taught C programming courses at Bellevue, Washington Community College.

1988 - 1989	<ul> <li>Data Comm Group Lead, North American Morpho Systems, Inc., Tacoma, WA</li> <li>Data communications group lead for a fingerprint id system software company</li> </ul>
1982 - 1989	Member of Technical Staff, Bell Laboratories, Holmdel, NJ
	• Designed and optimized algorithms for private telecommunications networks.
	Systems Engineer for digital telecomm services

#### **EDUCATION**

1982	Master of Science in Applied Mathematics University of Colorado: Boulder, CO
1980	Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics University of Colorado: Boulder, CO

## **VETERAN STATUS**

1972-1976 Honorable Discharge, U.S. Navy